A Guide to the Governor James Patton Preston Executive Papers, 1816-1819
Library of Virginia
James Paxton was appointed commandant of the newly constructed Lexington Arsenal in 1818. Paxton submits weekly returns of the Public Guard at the Arsenal (1818 Sept. 29, Oct. 27, Nov. 2, & Dec. 8). Later, Paxton sends half monthly returns (1819 July 14, Oct. 31, & Nov. 30). In addition, Paxton writes to the Governor with respect to the following topics: the grounds of the Arsenal & gun racks (1818 March 18); the recruiting of the guard at the Arsenal (1818 May 29); the claim of Jefferson Caruthers for taking care of the buildings at the Arsenal, his pay, supplies, & enlistments (1818 June 10); accepting his position as paymaster to the guard at the Arsenal (1818 July 11); an estimate of the expense for enclosing the Arsenal (1818 July 12); pay for his services (1818 Aug. 1); supplies for recruiting at the Arsenal (1818 Aug. 18); muster & pay rolls at the Arsenal (1818 Aug. 20); the enclosure of the Arsenal (1818 Sept. 21); the desertion of a soldier Stephen Jarvis (1818 Sept. 29); the desertion of Henry Miller (1818 Oct. 27); muster & pay rolls & his subsistence account (1818 Oct. 28); improvements to the Arsenal (1818 Nov. 17); fuel for the arsenal (1819 Jan. 12); pay & subsistence account for January 1819 (1819 Feb. 3); the employment of a surgeon & winter clothing for the guard (1819 Feb. 6); accounts for bounties, premiums, & contingent expenses (1819 July 14); the account of Davidson & Gilmore for timber delivered to complete the gun racks at the Arsenal (1819 July 20); his conduct as commandant of the Lexington Arsenal (1819 Aug. 12); an abstract of provisions furnished by John Jordan to the guard at the Arsenal (1819 Nov. 11); and contracts for rations (1819 Nov. 27).
Peter Crutchfield, Commandant of the Public Guard, provides a monthly muster roll of the Public Guard (1818 June [N.D.]). Blair Bolling replaced Peter Crutchfield as Commandant of the Public Guard in 1818. In a letter to the Governor on 31 July, Bolling accepts his appointment. Bolling also writes regarding a recommendation of the discharge of a soldier (1818 Sept. 8); returns for fuel (1818 Oct. 1); the discharge of Thomas Davis (1818 Dec. 9 & 12); weekly returns of the Public Guard (1819 Feb. 8); the morning report of the Public Guard (1819 March 10); a railing from the corner of the Barracks to the corner of the enclosure of the Capitol Square & the removal of the steps (1819 April 6); cap cords for the uniforms furnished for the Public Guard by the Penitentiary (1819 May 28); the detail of the Public Guard for cleaning the Public Necessary (1819 July 16 & 19); and the report of the Public Guard (1819 Oct. 31).
John Staples, as Superintendent of the Virginia Manufactory of Arms, corresponds with the Governor regarding Daniel Pettibone's letter on the subject of improvements in welding cast steel to iron (1817 March 27) and the plastering of the inside of the Lexington Arsenal (1817 Aug. 25). Additionally, Staples provides a statement of the operations of the Manufactory of Arms for the year ending 30 November 1817 & a statement of the number & description of public arms on hand at the Armory (1817 Dec. 1).
Samuel P. Parsons, Keeper of the Penitentiary, communicates with Governor Preston regarding his refusal to certify the agent's invoice of purchases (1817 Jan. 9); his nomination of William Jarvis as 1st assistant & Thomas Jones as 4th assistant in the Penitentiary (1817 March 27); clothing for the Public Guard (1817 April 25); a list of convicts confined in the Penitentiary for sale & transportation (1817 June 30); the sale of seven transport slaves to Henry King (1817 July 1); the quarterly account of the Penitentiary (1817 July 6); the recommendation of Abner Griffin as turnkey & sergeant to the Penitentiary (1817 Sept. 18); the remaining convicts in the Penitentiary for sale & transportation (1817 Dec. 17); rations for the Penitentiary (1818 March 4); the house originally intended for the Keeper of the Penitentiary (1818 March 9); the advertisement in The Compiler notifying the public that the Keeper of the Penitentiary is authorized to supply the institution with raw materials (1818 March 12); the case of Jonathan Parker & Alexander McCrackon confined in the Penitentiary for grand larceny (1818 March 20); the nomination of Daniel Tolly as Assistant Keeper of the Penitentiary (1818 May 9); the account for the workmanship & materials in erecting the new building at the Penitentiary (1818 July 23); the recommendation of Andrew M. Crew as turnkey & repairs to the wells in the Penitentiary (1818 Oct. 28); weekly returns & the transportation of arms to the Arsenal (1818 Nov. 23); the cases of Thomas Howard, Presley Jennings, & William Welsh (1819 Jan. 30); and recommendations of David Potty as 3rd Assistant Keeper & William Simpson as 4th Assistant Keeper (1819 April 3).
Philip Norborne Nicholas, Attorney General, provides opinions on slaves condemned to death & reprieved from transportation (817 Feb. 24); the claim of Richard Clough Anderson as principal surveyor of the lands given by law to the officers & soldiers on Continental & State establishments in Kentucky (1817 Dec. 15); claims against the Ship George & Brig Adams relative to certain quarantine charges (1818 Jan. 19); the claim of Jacob Beeson as agent on behalf of the Commonwealth (1818 Jan. 19); the authority of the superior & inferior courts to imprison for contempt of court for periods longer than the duration of the terms of those courts & whether the Executive has the authority to pardon them (1818 Jan. 30); the authority of the Executive to decide on the propriety of paying the Keeper of the Penitentiary additional compensation (1818 March 27); the power of the Executive to appoint directors for the North Western Bank (1818 June 21); the title of the hemp house lot (1818 June 23); the case of Pleasant W. Harwood (1818 July 29); and the writ of forcible entry & detainer brought by Richard Young against the soldiers of the Public Guard relative to the Hemp House lot (1818 Aug. 6). Nicholas resigned as attorney general in a letter to the Governor dated 8 January 1819 and was replaced by John Robertson. Robertson provides an opinion on the case of an individual claiming money to be paid by the Commonwealth through the Executive who made a false affidavit (1819 April 6).
William Munford, as Clerk of the House of Delegates, often submits legislation to the Governor. Noteworthy is a resolution of the House of Delegates that the Governor & Council be requested and the Treasurer instructed to appoint no person suspected of committing usurious practices (1817 Jan. 4); a resolution that the Executive be requested to lay before the Assembly the reports of the Adjutant General in relation to the public edifices, Public Guard, munitions of war, & public property (1817 Jan. 20); an act for providing seals for the Superior Courts of Law (1818 Jan. 10); a resolution that the Executive lay before the House copies of all existing contracts for repairing & improving the Capitol or Public Square (1818 Feb. 7); an act to provide for the collection of the arrears of the Commonwealth's revenue due prior to January 1819 (1819 Jan. 12); a resolution that the Solicitor's Office in the basement story of the Capitol be fitted up & set apart for the use of the Board of Public Works (1819 Feb. 1); an act concerning the publication of the statutes at large (1819 March 10); and a resolution of the House of Delegates regarding the election of James Pleasants as a senator in Congress to supply the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of James W. Eppes (1819 Dec. 10).
Additionally, Munford transmits certificates of the elections of the following individuals: John Preston as Treasurer (1817 Jan. 17); William F. Pendleton as a member of the Privy Council (1817 Jan. 21); Jerman Baker & John M. Martin as members of the Privy Council (1818 Jan. 4); John W. Greene as judge of the Superior Courts of Chancery at Williamsburg & Fredericksburg (1818 Dec. 11); and Thomas Mann Randolph as governor (1819 Dec. 10).
William Robertson, Clerk of the Council of State, often submits the advice of the Council to the Governor. Significant advice by the Council include the following: the discharge of Orris Paine as Superintendent of Improvements (1818 Feb. 17); contracts for stone to set the foot of each brace to secure the iron railing around the Public Square, for cutting away the earth near the Barracks, for coping the stone for the braces, & for building a brick wall near the Governor's kitchen (1818 April 23); the leasing of the Foundry & Boring Mill, pardons, & a bounty to recruits under Capt. James Paxton (1818 April 24); and the opinion of Philip N. Nicholas regarding the case of Joseph Towns who was commissioned sheriff of Mecklenburg County in 1815 (1818 June 12). In addition, there is an advertisement to be published in several newspapers soliciting a model of the monument to be erected to Gen. George Washington (1818 June 17).
John Burfoot, Auditor of Public Accounts, corresponds with Governor Preston regarding various financial matters. Burfoot requests advances for sending out public riders to issue notices of delinquencies (1817 March 24 & Sept. 18). In addition, Burfoot writes to discuss arrearages of taxes in various counties without sheriffs (1817 April 10); a warrant for Edmund Saunders, Clerk of the Auditor of Public Accounts, for notices of public delinquents (1817 May 31); the repair & improvement of his office in the Capitol (1817 June 20); a statement of the taxes on lands sold for the nonpayment of taxes in Lee County (1817 July 28); the abolition of the Accountant's Office (1817 Dec. 10); the expense of riders to give notice to delinquent sheriffs (1818 June 13; 1819 June 10; & 1819 Nov. 19); an additional clerk (1818 April 18); delinquent sheriffs in Harrison County (1818 June 26); returns against delinquent sheriffs in Harrison County (1818 July 16); his leaving of office after Oct. 15 (1818 Oct. 6); presses for papers in the Auditor's Office (1819 March 15); the collection of the revenue of Norfolk County & Princess Anne County (1819 May 27); and accounts with the U. S. & lands under execution in Harrison County (1819 Oct. 6).
John Wood corresponded with the Governor regarding his work in charting Virginia's river and creating maps of Virginia's counties. On 15 December 1816, Wood writes regarding his chart of the James River, the boundaries of the counties, and the latitude & longitude of particular places in the state. Wood also writes regarding his proposal to complete a chart of Virginia in five years (1817 April 4); his proposal to survey the state for the proposed chart of Virginia (1817 May 12); the completion of his survey of the Piankitank & one side of the Rappahannock River (1817 June 23); an account of the surveys of the Rappahannock & Piankitank rivers (1817 July 23); the completion of the survey of the York River & the beginning of the survey of the Chesapeake Bay from Cape Henry (1817 Aug. 13); the survey of the Bay Shore between Cape Henry & the North River (1817 Aug. 23); charts of the York River, the Virginia side of the Potomac River, & the Bay Shore from Lynhaven Creek to North River & Smith's Point (1817 Oct. 20); an alteration of his contract in surveying the Bay Shore & North River (1818 June 1); the charts of the Chickahominy, Pamunkey, & Mattaponi rivers (1818 Oct. 12); advances for his work to create charts of each county & a general map of the Commonwealth (1819 March 23 & April 5); the survey of the Chickahominy River (1819 May 11); and the completion of maps for ten counties (1819 Oct. 25).
John Chew was appointed to settle the accounts of Virginia with the United States for expenses incurred during the War of 1812. Chew writes to Governor Preston on several occasions with respect to the progress of the settlement of the claims of Virginia against the General Government (1817 April 9); the remarks of the examining clerks upon the accounts & vouchers from Virginia (1817 April 17); his arrival in Richmond with $250,000 from the U. S. Treasury on account of the claims of Virginia for expenses in the late war (1817 May 5); compensation for his services since 6 May 1817 (1818 Aug. 19); muskets returned to Richmond & arms given by the General Government to militia encamped at Elliot's Mill in Maryland (1818 Sept. 14); the order for the transportation & delivery of arms due for the quota of the state of Virginia under the act of Congress dated 23 April 1808 (1818 Oct. 9); and the settlement of the last account of Virginia with the United States. (1819 Dec. 8).
Governors from other states comprise a significant amount of correspondence received by the Governor. This correspondence primarily relates to amendments to the U. S. Constitution, extraditions, and the distribution of laws. Included are letters from the following governors: William Miller & John Branch, North Carolina; William Jones, Rhode Island; John Tayler & DeWitt Clinton, New York; Thomas Worthington & Ethan A. Brown, Ohio; Gabriel Slaughter, Kentucky; John Brooks, Massachusetts; Andrew Pickens, South Carolina; William Plumer, New Hampshire; Oliver Wolcott, Connecticut; David Holmes, Mississippi; Jacques Philippe Villere, Louisiana, Charles Goldsborough, Maryland; and William Findlay, Pennsylvania.
Governor William Miller, North Carolina, transmits an act of the North Carolina General Assembly respecting the Dismal Swamp Canal Company (1817 Jan. 2). Later, John Branch writes regarding a demand for High R. Irvine, a fugitive from justice (1818 March 26). William Jones, Rhode Island, acknowledges receipt of the journals of the Virginia Conventions of 1775 & 1776 (1817 April 17). John Tayler, N. Y., also writes to acknowledge receipt of the journals (1817 April 24). Governors Thomas Worthington, Ohio; Gabriel Slaughter, Kentucky; Andrew Pickens, South Carolina; DeWitt Clinton, N. Y.; & David Holmes, Mississippi; transmit copies of the recently passed laws (1817 June 5; 1817 Sept. 26; & 1818 Feb. 16; 1818 July 13; 1819 July 22, 1819 Aug. 30). Governor John Brooks, Massachusetts, encloses a copy of the proceedings of the Council regarding William Ryan, a fugitive from justice (1818 Feb. 11). Governor William Plumer, New Hampshire; DeWitt Clinton, N. Y.; & David Holmes, Mississippi; enclose resolutions for an amendment to the U. S. Constitution to divide each state into districts for the purpose of electing representatives in Congress (1818 Aug.). Governor Gabriel Slaughter, Kentucky, writes concerning the resolution of Virginia to appoint a commissioner to inspect the obstructions on the Ohio River (1818 Oct. 22). Governor Thomas Worthington, Ohio, encloses resolutions regarding amendments to the Constitution related to choosing Representatives in Congress & compensation to members of Congress (1818 Dec. 7). Worthington also writes regarding receipt of the resolution of Virginia regarding the improvement of the navigation of the Ohio River (1818 Dec. 8). Later, Governor Ethan A. Brown, Ohio, writes regarding the appointment of Gen. Edward W. Tupper as commissioner on the part of Ohio to survey the Ohio River (1819 April 30). Governor Jacques Philippe Villere, Louisiana, transmits a set of Martin's Digest of the Statutes of Louisiana (1818 Dec. 8). Governor Charles Goldsborough, Maryland, writes regarding the demand for John Baker (1819 June 5), the demand for Jesse McCoy (1819 June 14), the demand for Thomas Barnes (1819 June 30), the cases of both McCoy & Barnes (1819 June 30), and the demand of Martin F. Maker (1819 Nov. 29). Lastly, Governor William Findlay, Pennsylvania, encloses a copy of a presentment against Daniel Miller for committing fornication (1819 Nov. 8).
Additional significant correspondence includes the following: Griffin Stith accepting an appointment as judge of the General Court (1816 Dec. 14); Edmund Pendleton Gaines acknowledging receipt of the resolutions of the General Assembly re. his conduct in the defense of Ft. Erie in 1814 (1816 Dec. 22); Robert Quarles, Quarter Master General, re. the need for clerks (1817 Jan. 13); Arthur Smith resigning as a member of the Privy Council (1817 Jan. 16); Richard Young re. a new edition of a map of Richmond which he wishes to delineate on the Public Square the contemplated improvements according to the plan made by Maximillian Godefroy (1817 Jan. 24); John Binns transmitting his proposal to print an edition of the Declaration of Independence (1817 March 6); James Smith, U.S. Agent for Vaccination, encl. his bond & printed regulations of the general institution for the preservation & distribution of vaccine matter (1817 March 26); James Warrell re. his museum & infringements by some of the improvements to Capitol Square (1817 Feb. 24); Robert Quarles encl. a general return of quarter master stores, ammunition, arms, & ordnance (1817 March 18); William Munford re. the removal of his office as Keeper of the Rolls to the apartment in the Capitol formerly occupied by the Committee for Courts of Justice (1817 May 16); Preston Smith requesting permission to occupy the Senate Chamber as the Treasury Office during the summer months (1817 May 27); Frederick Clarke encl. a letter from Peter F. Smith re. the value of a lot adjoining the Capitol Square (1817 June 26); David Robertson re. the death of Griffin Stith, judge of the Circuit Court in Petersburg (187 July 13); John W. Eppes re. his certificate of election as senator in Congress (1817 Dec. 1); Henry Banks encl. a report, letter, & map of a new road from Kentucky to Virginia (1818 Jan. 10); Thomas R. Joynes encl. a presentment of a grand jury at a Superior Court of Law held for Accomack County of Southy Lucas & Noah Small for stealing two freedmen (1818 Jan. 3); John Preston re. the purchase of part of the Governor's lot (1818 Feb. 10); Board of Directors of the Penitentiary re. the statement of the operations of the Penitentiary from 1 December 1817 to 28 February 1818 (1818 Feb. [N.D.]); J. Oldham re. the appointment of commissioners to examine & value the work done on the Capitol under contract with the Executive or Orris Paine (1818 March 19); Charles Everette resigning as a member of the Council of State to become a candidate in the next Assembly (1818 March 28); acceptance letters for commissioners for fixing the site of the University (1818 April); Samuel Brooks encl. designs for the seals of the Superior Courts of Randolph & Scott counties (1818 April 13); James Madison accepting his appointment as commissioner for the University (1818 May 22); Lewis Hoff, Cashier, encl. reports of the Bank of the Valley (1818 June 25); Hugh Nelson re. the death of his brother Robert, Chancellor of the District of Williamsburg (1818 July 10); Robert Saunders re. the death of Robert Nelson and the recommendation of William Browne as his replacement (1818 July 11); Thomas Jefferson accepting the appointment as one of the commissioners to fix the site for the University (1818 July 13); Lt. E. Brown, Public Guard, requesting permission to level down & regulate the surface so as to extend the limits of the parade grounds (1818 July 17); William C. Greenup, Secretary of the Illinois Convention, transmitting a copy of the Constitution of the State of Illinois (1818 Sept. 11); Linah Mims resigning from the Privy Council (1818 Oct. 1); Ethan A. Clay, U. S. Armory Springfield, applying for the position of Superintendent of the Armory in Richmond (1818 Nov. 9); Bernard Peyton, Secretary of the Board of Public Works, encl. a resolution requesting a suitable apartment in the Capitol for the safekeeping of books, maps, charts, & papers (1818 Nov. 23); William W. Hening re. the state of the Chancery Office (1818 Nov. 26); William Hening re. the publication of the Statutes At Large (1819 March 17 & May 26); Alden Bradford, Secretary of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, re. the arrest of Curtis McLeister charged with a crime in Virginia (1819 June 12); John Marshall re. prisoners charged with piracy & requesting permission to confine them in the Penitentiary (1819 July 2); John Adams, Mayor of Richmond, re. the prevalence of yellow fever in the West Indies & the enforcement of quarantine laws of the state (1819 July 16 & Aug. 19); P. N. Nicholas re. designs of a monument to be erected to the memory of George Washington by Maximillian Godefroy (1819 Aug. 16 & 18); and Thomas T. Tucker, U. S. Treasury, re. a list of payments made to John Chew (1819 Nov. 23).
Other noteworthy items include: quarterly reports of the Board of Visitors of the Penitentiary (1816 Dec. 31; 1817 Jan. 18 & 22; 1817 July 19; 1817 Dec. 20; 1818 Jan. 2, 6, & 23; 1818 Feb. 28; 1818 March 7; 1818 April 10; 1818 May 23; 1818 Aug. 22; 1818 Sept. 11; 1818 Oct. 10; 1819 Jan. 16; 1819 Feb. 3 & 20;1819 March 2; 1819 April 24; 1819 June 12; 1819 July 17 & 24; 1819 Aug. 7; & 1819 Nov. 20); bonds of John Burfoot as Auditor of Public Accounts (1817 Jan. 3; 1818 Jan. 1; & 1819 Jan. 1); oath of qualification from James E. Heath as a member of the Privy Council (1817 Jan. 7); bond of William G. Pendleton as Register of the Land Office (1817 Jan. 7); contract between Thomas Strode & John P. Shields (1817 Jan. 13); proclamations by Governor Preston & Lt. Governor Peter V. Daniel offering rewards for the apprehension of criminals (1817 Jan. 15; 1817 Feb. 17; 1817 July 9; 1817 Nov. 1; 1817 Dec. 2 & 20; 1818 Feb. 9 & 19; 1818 April 25; 1818 May 29; 1818 July 29; 1818 Sept. 21; 1818 Oct. 9; 1818 Nov. 3 & 13; 1818 Dec. 4; 1819 Jan. 5 & 8; 1819 April 6 & 12; 1819 May 10, 27, & 28; 1819 June 10; 1819 July 14; 1819 Aug. 17 & 18; 1819 Oct. 6 & 29); report of the committee appointed by the Executive to lay off the City of Richmond into wards (1817 March 20); the proposal of Sewall Osgood & William Lee for enclosing the Capitol Square (1817 April 10); applications for Door Keeper for the Council (1817 May & June); account of Cook & War for grooving & soldering copper, etc. (1817 June 3); receipts of P. A. Sabbaton for advances on the contract for enclosing the Public Square (1817 July 10 & Nov. 4); proclamation of Governor Preston ordering the quarantine of all vessels suspected of carrying yellow fever (1817 July 15); account of Baker Bevins for slating the Capitol (1817 July 20); contract of Edward W. Trent to set the stone around the Public Square on which the iron railing is to be fixed (1817 Aug. 12); petition of the Public Guard for an increase in wages or compensation for extra duties (1817 Oct. 9); petition of the Nottoway Indians choosing trustees (1817 Oct. 11); account of John Bosher for carpenter's work for the governor's new stable (1817 Nov. [N.D.]); proclamation of Governor Preston revoking his proclamation of 15 July directing the performance of quarantine (1817 Dec. 5); account of James Kinkead for furnishing stone for the Capitol (1817 Dec. 6); receipt of James Smith for work done in the Capitol (1817 Dec. 29); account of John Anderson for digging earth out of the Governor's lot (1817 Dec. [N.D.]); certificates of Jerman Baker & John M. Martin as members of the Privy Council (1818 Jan. 7); certificate of oath of Capt. James Paxton as lieutenant commandant of the Lexington Arsenal (1818 Jan. 28); demand of Gov. Preston for Thomas Spiers, a fugitive of justice in North Carolina (1818 Feb. 4); bond of John Staples as Superintendent of the Manufactory of Arms (1818 Feb. 14); report of the commissioners to settle the accounts of former trustees for the Nottoway & Nansemond Indians (1818 Feb. 28); report of the committee to communicate copies of all existing contracts for repairing & improving the Capitol or Public Square (1818 Feb. [N.D.]; account by C. Tompkins of the measurements for the stucco & plastering done by Mr. Gill on the Capitol (1818 March 28); contract between the Governor & John Jordan to furnish rations for the guard at the Lexington Arsenal (1818 March 30); contract between the Governor & A. S. Brockenbrough to perform the duties of superintendent of the gradation & improvement of the Public Square or repairing or improving the Capitol conformably to Godefroy's plan (1818 April 1); proclamation of Governor Preston re. the Bank of the Valley of Virginia (1818 May 7); contract between A. S. Brockenbrough & Orris Paine, administrator of James Kinkead, to furnish granite stones for the enclosure of the Public Square (1818 May 15); accounts of J. Oldham for repairs of carpenter's work done on the Capitol in 1816 & 1817 (1818 May 20); contract between Arthur S. Brockenbrough & Robert Linn to furnish iron braces for the enclosure of the Public Square (1818 May 25); contract between A. S. Brockenbrough and Bailey & Horton to build a wall on the Public Square (1818 May 25); proclamation of Governor Preston authorizing & directing that the courts for Westmoreland County be held at the house of Thomas Spence until a new courthouse is built (1818 June 5); bond of Richard Holstead as Inspector General of Lumber for the Borough of Norfolk (1818 June 6); bond of William H. Hening as agent for the distribution of vaccine matter (1818 July 8); proclamation of Governor Preston for all superintendents of quarantine to perform quarantine for twenty days (1818 July 23); contract between A. S. Brockenbrough & William G. Goodson for the carpenter's work for the Public Privy (1818 Sept. 1); proclamation of Governor Preston revoking his proclamation of 22 July for the performance of quarantine (1818 Dec. 9); certificate of oath for James Patton Preston as governor (1818 Dec. 15); report of the committee appointed to investigate the state of accounts relative to the improvement of the Capitol & Public Square with estimates to complete the various improvements on the Capitol & the Public Square (1818 [N.D.]); proclamation of Governor Preston authorizing the North Western Bank of Virginia to being operations (1819 Jan. 16); proclamation of Governor Preston re. a reward for the apprehension of the perpetrator who broke into the Magazine in Richmond to steal gun powder (1819 Feb. 20); proclamation of Governor Preston re. a reward for the apprehension of the perpetrator who killed a slave named Mingo who was pardoned by the Executive (1819 Feb. 22); proclamation of Governor Preston re. the formation of the several Boards of Principal Assessors (1819 March 15); account of Thomas B. Conway for work done on the Capitol Square (1819 March 23); contract between Orris Paine & Arthur S. Brockenbrough to dig & carry off the earth from the foundation of the stone wall to be put up on Capitol & 13th Street around the Governor's lot (1819 March 31); contract of John Wood to make an accurate chart of each county and a general map of the Commonwealth (1819 April 1); contract between Orris Paine & A. S. Brockenbrough to furnish & set granite plinths for the wall parts for the steps of the Capitol (1819 April 8); contract between Robert Barz & Jeremiah Keenan & A. S. Brockenbrough to undertake the carpenter's & joiner's work of the Governor's stable (1819 May 14); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Peter V. Daniel re. the quarantine of any vessels infected with any contagious disease (1819 Aug. 19); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Peter V. Daniel convening the Board of Principal Assessors (1819 Oct. 1); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Peter V. Daniel re. a reward for the apprehension of the persons who murdered Martin Mims, the receiver of tolls at Trent's Bridge (1819 Oct. 6); proclamation of Lt. Gov. Peter V. Daniel discontinuing quarantine (1819 Oct. 6); a report of the committee appointed to examine into the condition of the Auditor's Office (1819 Nov. 7); an account of P. A. Sabbaton for putting up three thousand feet of railing (1819 Nov. 10); proclamation of Governor Preston re. the demand of the state of Pennsylvania for Daniel Miller (1819 Nov. 16); contract between the Executive & Carter & Blake to prepare cotton backs for the plans of John Wood (1819 Nov. 22); report of John Preston, Treasurer, to the General Assembly (1819 Dec. [N.D.]; contract between the Governor & Christopher Tompkins & Thomas B. Conway to cut & drill all the holes in the stone around the Capitol Square (Undated); and bills for the Arsenal & Barracks at Lexington (Undated).